Guide to the Scott and Gary Show Archive ca. 1983-1989 MSS 247
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
Scott and Gary Show Archive
ca. 1983-1989
MSS 247
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
4.0 boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Arrangement note
The collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Informational Binders
Series II: Video
Scope and Content note
The Scott and Gary Show Archive comprises materials related to the cable-access show, produced and hosted by Scott Lewis and Gary Winter, that ran from 1983 to 1989. Materials include videotapes of the show; photocopies of a chronology of the series, episode descriptions, correspondence, clippings, and photographs; and videotapes of Jeff Krulik's "A Tribute to the Scott and Gary Show", their appearance on the CBS-TV sitcom "Kate and Allie", and an in-depth video interview with the show's creators.
The collection is arranged into two series:
Series I: Informational Binders. This series contains photocopies of a chronology of the series, episode descriptions, correspondence, clippings, and photographs.
Series II: Video. This series is divided into two subseries. Subseries A contains access copies for the researcher. At present, access copies have not been created for all material. Please contact a Fales archivist. Subseries B contains original video elements.
Historical Note
The Scott and Gary Show was a cable access variety show that ran from 1983 to 1989 and featured punk and indie bands, live audience dance parties, and comedy skits. Created and hosted by Scott Lewis and Gary Winter, the show was filmed in New York City from 1983 to 1986 and, at the invitation of cable access producer Jeff Krulik, in the Washington DC metro area, from 1986 to 1989.
The show is notable for early appearances of bands such as the Butthole Surfers and the Beastie Boys (who appear with drummer Kate Schellenbach, later of Luscious Jackson). Other musical guests include the Ben Vaughn Combo, Raunch Hands, Half Japanese, Shockabilly, and Velvet Monkeys.
Separated Materials
Twenty videotapes were returned to donor Scot Lewis in September 2012. These deaccessioned materials are indicated in the finding aid. All videotapes were preserved by Fales, except for appearance on "Kate and Allie" television series. The repository holds preservation masters and access viewing copies for all other deaccessioned tapes.
Cable television |x Access.; Rock groups.; Videocassettes.
- Series I: Informational Binders
  - Scott and Gary Show Informational Binder I, 1983-2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scott and Gary Show Informational Binder II, 1983-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Video
  - Subseries A: Video Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Please ask a Fales Archivist for access.
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 101 -- Ben Vaughn, [1984] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0112)
      General note
      Format: DVD
      TRT: 0:30:00
      Original Format: U-matic
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 102 -- Beastie Boys, 1/29/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0109)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 103 -- 1/2 Japanese, 2/4/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0139)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 104 -- R. Stevie Moore, 4/1/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0121)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 105 -- The Raunch Hands, 4/29/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0127)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 106 -- Curtis A, 5/26/84 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0115)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 201 -- Butthole Surfers, [1985] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0145)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 202 -- The Johnsons, 1/11/85 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0130)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 203 -- No King, [1985] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0142)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 212 -- The Alterboys, [1985] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0133)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 213 -- The Clintons, [1985] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0118)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 10 -- Woofing Cookies, 3/26/[85] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0136)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 11 -- Shockabilly, 3/30/85 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0124)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 18 -- Beatoes, [1985] (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0046)
      General Note
      TRT: [00:57:00]
    - The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot) -- The Velvet Monkeys, 7/12/86 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0043)
      TRT: [00:43:41]
    - The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot) Episode 14 -- The Rhomboids, 7/12/86 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0040)
    - Elvis #1, Tape 1 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0066)
      TRT: [00:21:00]
      Original Format: Betacam
    - Elvis #2, Tape 2 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0069)
      TRT: [00:15:30]
    - Elvis #3, Tape 3 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0072)
      TRT: [00:18:15]
    - Elvis #4, Tape 4 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0075)
      TRT: [00:20:30]
    - Elvis #5, Tape 5 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0078)
      TRT: [00:18:20]
    - Elvis #6, Tape 6 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0081)
    - Elvis #7, Tape 7 of 7, 8/1/87 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0084)
      TRT: [00:02:20]
    - The Scott and Gary Interviews, Disc 1 of 3, 2/2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0087)
      TRT: [01:05:00]
      Original Format: DVD-R
    - The Scott and Gary Interviews, Disc 2 of 3, 2/2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0090)
    - The Scott and Gary Interviews, Disc 3 of 3, 2/2000 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0093)
    - Scott and Gary Go To VH1, 2001 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0061)
      TRT: [00:12:00]
      Original Format: VHS
    - Jeff Krulik Presents a Tribute to The Scott and Gary Show, 6/15/04 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0063)
      TRT: [01:17:45]
    - Before They Were Rock Stars, #46, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0058)
      TRT: [00:24:00]
    - The Scott and Gary Show -- Beatnik Fly, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0055)
      TRT: [01:01:10]
    - The Scott and Gary Show -- Ben Vaughn and Aldo Jones, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0052)
      TRT: [00:59:17]
    - The Scott and Gary Show -- Das Yahoos, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 247.0049)
      TRT: [01:01:11]
  - Subseries B: Video Originals
    Original material may not be available for consultation. Please ask a Fales archivist for access. Also see Series II: Subseries A: Video Access Copies
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 102--Beastie Boys, 1/29/84 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0001)
      Format: 1" video
      TRT: [unknown]
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 102--Beastie Boys [MASTER], 1/29/84 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0094)
      Format: U-Matic
      TRT: [00:28:00]
      Separated Materials
      Videotape returned to donor.
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 103--1/2 Japanese, 2/4/84 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0104)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 103--1/2 Japanese, 2/4/84 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0002)
      TRT: Unknown
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 104--R. Stevie Moore [MASTER], 4/1/84 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0098)
      TRT: [00:30:15]
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 105-- The Raunch Hands, 4/29/84 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0100)
    - The Scott and Gary Show--The Raunch Hands, 4/29/84 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0009)
      TRT: unknown
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 105--Curtis A, 5/26/84 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0004)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 106--Curtis A [MASTER], 5/26/84 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0096)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 202--The Johnsons [MASTER], 1/11/85 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0101)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 202--The Johnsons, 1/11/85 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0006)
    - (DEACCESSIONED) "Scott and Gary #10" -- Woofing Cookies, 3/26/[85] (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0103)
    - (DEACCESSIONED) Scott and Gary #11--Shockabilly [MASTER], 3/30/85 (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0099)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot)-- Episode 14--The Rhomboids, 7/12/86 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0011)
      Format: 3/4" Umatic
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show (Maryland Shoot)--The Velvet Monkeys, 7/12/86 (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0012)
    - Scott and Gary Show--Shockabilly, [August 19, 1986] (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0036)
      TRT: 32:00
    - Elvis #1, Tape 1 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0017)
      Format: Betacam
    - Elvis #2, Tape 2 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0018)
    - Elvis #3, Tape 3 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0019)
    - Elvis #4, Tape 4 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0020)
    - Elvis #5, Tape 5 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0021)
    - Elvis #6, Tape 6 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0022)
    - Elvis #7, Tape 7 of 7, 8/1/87 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0023)
      Arrangement note
      Material arranged by format and by chronological order.
    - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 1 of 3 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0029)
      Format: DVD-R
      TRT: 01:05:00
    - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 2 of 3 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0030)
    - Scott and Gary Interviews, 2/2000; Disc 3 of 3 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0031)
    - Scott and Gary Go To VH1 (2001) (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0028)
      Format: VHS-C
      TRT: 28:30
    - Altar boys, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0034)
    - Before They Were Rock Stars, #46, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0026)
      Format: VHS
    - Jeff Krulik Presents: A Tribute to The Scott and Gary Show, 6/15/04 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0027)
      TRT: 01:30:00
    - Jeff Krulik Presents a Tribute to the Scott and Gary Show, 6/15/04 (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0033)
      Format: Betacam SP
    - N.D.F., undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0037)
      TRT: 60:00
    - (DEACCESSIONED)Scott and Gary on Kate and Allie, undated (Box 4, Media ID: 247.0032)
      Videotape returned to donor. Fales does not have this title preserved.
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Beatnik Fly, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0016)
      TRT: 00:57:30
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Ben Vaughn and Aldo Jones, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0015)
    - The Scott and Gary Show--Clintons, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0007)
    - The Scott and Gary Show--Danny Barfman, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0025)
      Format: Betamax
    - The Scott and Gary Show--Elvis, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0024)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show--Das Yahoos, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0014)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 18--Beatoes, undated (Box 3, Media ID: 247.0013)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 101--Ben Vaughn, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0035)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 101--Ben Vaughn, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0095)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 104--Stevee Moore, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0003)
    - The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 201--The Butthole Surfers, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0005)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 201--The Butthole Surfers [MASTER], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0106)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 203--No King, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0105)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 212--The Alterboys [MASTER], undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0102)
    - (DEACCESSIONED)The Scott and Gary Show, Episode 213--The Clintons, undated (Box 5, Media ID: 247.0097)
      TRT: [00:30:00]
    - The Scott and Gary Show--No King, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0008)
    - The Scott and Gary Show--Woofing Cookies, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 247.0010)